Renata Reinartz

FRONT END DEVELOPER, Calgary, AB Canada

 $- renata.techie@gmail.com - \underline{www.linkedin.com/in/renata1026} - \underline{www.renata-reinartz.com} - \underline{www.github.com/renata1026} - \underline{www.github.com/r$

SUMMARY

I'm a Front-end Web Developer with experience using **HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, React, Javascript**, and **WordPress** to create accessible, responsive, and engaging sites and apps. My previous experience as a senior accountant and CPA gives me a strong understanding of *business processes, user needs*, and *leadership*, which translates well to development work.

EDUCATION

WEB DEVELOPMENT IMMERSIVE BOOTCAMP

SEPT 2022 — FEB 2023

Juno College of Technology, Toronto - Remote

- Courseworks: Front End Development, Javascript & React Fundamentals, Responsive Design
- Skills: Paired Programming, Project Presentation, and Team Collaboration

Chartered Professional Accountant

JUNE 2015

University of Lethbridge, Bachelor of Management, Major: Accounting

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- LANGUAGES: HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, Firebase;
- FRAMEWORK: React:
- TOOLS: vsCode, Git & Command Line Tools, Netlify, Rest APIs, Version Control, Wireframing & Scope;
- OTHER: Google Analytics, ConvertKit, MailChimp, Lighthouse

PROJECTS & RELEVANT EXPERIENCES

Web Developer Freelancer

OCT 2021 — PRESENT

• Design modern and pleasing WordPress websites leading to increased traffic for clients for the Ambitious Assistant, Lift Your Vibe, and Styled By Sasla.

Linda Barutha | Remote

JUNE 2022 — OCT 2022

- Develop effective landing pages and pop-ups to increase signups.
- Installation of Google Analytics and SEO plug-ins to improve SEO ranking and track client traffic.
- Integrate email marketing system and create email campaigns to increase client conversion.

Student Mentor MAR 2023 — PRESENT

Juno College | Remote

- Provide guidance to Juno College Students via HelpCue and assist them with any code related problems.
- Maintain a welcoming environment where students are encouraged to ask any questions and ensure they have a full understanding of the content.

Find Your Podcast, www.podcast-planner-app.netlify.app

FEB 2023

www.github.com/renata1026/podcast-planner

• A fun app where the user selects the length of their podcast using a slider and the genre of the podcast using the listennotesAPI. The user can also save to their playlist or delete their selection. Developed and designed collaboratively using peer programming techniques.

Choose Your Makeup, www.makeup4life.netlify.app

www.github.com/makeup-ecommerce-store

JAN 2023

• An elegantly designed and developed e-commerce website using React and the makeup API. The user can select the price and product they want and includes a scroll to the top function.

Renata Reinartz

FRONT END DEVELOPER, Calgary, AB Canada

— renata.techie@gmail.com — www.linkedin.com/in/renata1026 — www.renata-reinartz.com — www.github.com/renata1026

PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE

Online English Teacher/Evaluator

APR 2018 — AUG 2021

Whales English | Remote

- Promoted to an evaluator. Reviewed playback of over 40 teachers monthly (1000 + teachers in total) and wrote evaluation reports and suggestions for improvement which led to 30% higher client satisfaction and renewals
- Instructed ESL students in one-to-one and one-to-ten virtual settings using Zoom, with an
 established English curriculum, and tests that improved students' English speaking and writing
 abilities. Wrote weekly feedback and suggestions which led to higher marks and improved their
 fluency

Accounting Manager

MAR 2014 — DEC 2017

Pacekids Programs | Calgary, AB

- Converted the company's software to QuickBooks Pro and implemented an accrual-based accounting system with monthly cutoffs which led to 98% more accurate reporting
- Created a monthly cash flow report and financial package for the board of directors which led to better spending practices and a more balanced budget
- Previously an accountant and promoted to accounting manager

Previous positions included a Senior Financial Analyst, Accountant, and Corporate Reporting Analyst at multinational companies.

CLIENT TESTIMONIALS

"Renata is such a pleasure to work with. Not only is her skill set impressive, she always goes above and beyond. She is amazing at communicating throughout the entire process as well as making recommendations we would not have thought about. I look forward to continuing to work with Renata in the future!" Sandra Martin, Marketing Agency Owner, Her Business Society

"Renata is an awesome person who does fantastic work! She worked in my business for about 6 months and quickly became someone I could completely rely on to not only get the job done, but to always be focused on the client's happiness with her work." Linda Barutha, Done 4 You Website